Okay, this wouldn't be a modern
JavaScript course if we didn't talk
about import and export. So, what I've
shown you of bringing in your functions
from an external file by using another
script tag is definitely one way to
bring functions in. But in modern
JavaScript, we use import and export
instead. So, if you're going to be
working with things like React or other
libraries and frameworks, um you're
going to want to know import export. So,
let's start laying the groundwork for
that. So, what I'm going to do is I'm
going to get rid of this. I'm actually
going to comment out this script tag for
now. And we are going to create another
script tag right here. If you want to
use import export syntax, then you need
to specify the type of script tag you're
using. And in this case, we'll say we're
using a module. What a module is is it
says I'm going to be importing things
from an external file. Therefore, you
need to be okay with import and export
being used. So, we'll save that. Okay.
I'm going to come over here to this file
called test.j. js and I am going to use
the keyword export. So I'm saying export
default. Um what that means is if
someone wants to import something from
this file then the default thing we give
them is whatever comes after the word
default. So in this case I could export
the number nine and save it. So if we
come over here to test.html HTML. Um, if
I want to import it, I say import numbum
because I have to give it a name because
I'm just bringing in something from the
other file. If you notice over here, it
doesn't have a name. It's just the
number nine and it's the default thing
that's being exported. So, if we come
over here, I have to give it a name. So,
import num from and then where am I
importing from? So, I'll say dot slash
meaning start where I am. Look inside
the same folder as this file. So,
wherever test.html is and look for
test.js. JS. And then once I've brought
in the number, I'm going to log it. So
I'm going to say console.log num.
If I save this and we come over here, we
can see that nine got logged on the
console. Okay. Well, that's cool. What
else could we export? Let's change this
9 to 1 2 3 4. So it's an array. Now, if
we come over here, it's 1 2 3 4. Um, so
we can export arrays. We can export
numbers. What about strings?
Hello.
Oh, looks like we can export strings,
too. Well, interesting.
Let's try something else. So, I'm going
to create a function here. I'm going
call it add two numbers, and it's going
to take in an A and a B, and it's going
to return A + B.
So, we'll save that. Could we export an
entire function here?
Let's see. We'll save it and we'll come
over here and what gets printed is the
function itself.
Interesting. Okay. So, we know we can
bring in a function. Um,
and over here, oh, sorry. Over here,
when we bring it in, we have to give it
a name.
Well, wouldn't it be nice if we could
just bring in the name that already
existed in test.js?
Well, there is a way to do that. So,
rather than exporting a default um which
has no name because it's just the
default export, you can do another
export in your file. You can only have
one export default can have as many
exports as you want. Um but the syntax
for bringing them in is a little
different. And to demonstrate that,
we're actually going to move from using
test.js js um to using script.js.
Here in script, we wrote cleanup string
apply to array and round. Here in
test.html,
I'm going to comment this out and bring
back in this script. And we are using
apply to array, cleanup, string, and
round. And we're calling them by their
name. And it would be nice if we could
bring them in by name. Well, if we want
to bring them in, then we need to say
type equals module.
And then here we need to import them.
Well, things work a little Well,
actually, sorry. First, in the script,
we have to export them. So, I'm going to
add export to the front of these. We're
going to export multiple things from
this file. Remember, you can have as
many exports as you want, but you can
only have one export default per file.
So, we can now export all of these. and
they actually kept their name when we
export them. Which means if we want to
bring them in, we have to bring them in
by name. The syntax is slightly
different. So you'll say import
and then you'll use curly braces and
then you're going to write the name of
the functions that you want to bring in.
So I want to bring in clean up string.
I want to bring in round and I want to
bring in apply to array. And then where
do I want to get them from? Well, look
in the current folder I'm in for a file
called script.js.
We save that and we come to our running
code. We can see it successfully cleaned
up the three arrays and rounded them.
So,
if you want to bring in a default
import from another file, then you just
say import, you give it a name, and then
you say from that other file. If you
want to bring in something that has a
name and you want it to keep its name,
then in the other file you'll do an
export
and then you'll say import and then
using curly braces you'll specify the
names of the things that you want to
bring in. And that concludes this video
on import and export. I hope that was
helpful.